[Music]
foreign
these are the journals I try to stay on
top of every month but now I have a new
one to add to the list the international
Journal of disease reversal and
prevention a new peer-viewed medical
journal created to document the signs of
nutrition and lifestyle to prevent
suspend and reverse disease with an
endurance you've no less prestigious
than Dr Kim Williams chief of Cardiology
at rush and past president of the
American College of Cardiology I was
honored to join their editorial Advisory
Board along with so many of my heroes
and the best part is it's free go to
ijdrp.org and put in your email to
subscribe for free and you'll be alerted
when new issues are out which you can
download info for free in PDF form
instead of preventing chronic lifestyle
diseases we doctors just tend to manage
them instead of curing we just mitigate
why because of Finance culture habit
tradition yeah many of us Envision a
world where trillions of dollars are not
wasted on unnecessary Medical Care
for this reason comes the international
Journal of disease reversal and
prevention after all without data you're
just another person with an opinion just
to give you a taste how about pitting
plants against one of the most
inflammatory diseases out there the
lupus an autoimmune disease in which
your body can start attacking your own
DNA
kidney inflammation is a common
consequence and even with our
armamentarium of immunosuppressant drugs
and steroids lupus-induced kidney
inflammation can lead to end-stage renal
disease meaning dialysis and death
unless perhaps you pack your diet with
some of the most you know
anti-inflammatory foods out there and
your kidney function improves so much
you no longer need dialysis or a kidney
transplant another similar case is also
presented with a resolution in symptoms
and normal kidney function unless he
deviated from the diet
even just cunning out animal products
randomizing people to cut out meat eggs
and dairy without significantly
increasing fruit and vegetable intake
can cut C-reactive protein levels a
sensitive indicator of whole body
inflammation by nearly a third within
eight weeks but with lupus they weren't
messing around a pound of leafy greens
and cruciferous vegetables a day like
kale fruits like berries and lots of
chia or flax and a gallon of water a day
basically a green smoothie diet to
extinguish lupus flares note though if
your kidneys are already compromised
they should be done under physician
supervision so they can monitor your
electrolytes like potassium and make
sure you don't get you know overloaded
with fluid
bottom line with such remarkable
improvements due to dietary changes all
alone the hope is that researchers will
take up the mantle and formally put it
to the test autoimmune inflammatory skin
disease reversals can be particularly
striking visually a woman with a 35-year
history of psoriasis unsuccessfully
managed for year after year with drugs
suffering from other autoimmune
conditions like Sjogren's as well but
put her on an extraordinarily healthy
diet packed with greens and other
vegetables fruits nuts seeds avocados
some whole grains and boom before
and after
within a year she went from 40 percent
of her entire body surface area inflamed
and affected down to zero percent
completely clear oh and her sjogren
symptoms resolved as well as a bonus
while helping to normalize her weight
and cholesterol
speaking of autoimmune diseases what
about the treatment of type 1 diabetes
with plants we'll find out next
thank you